<system>
  <title>Manager</title>
  <short-description>
    HCI-based task management, cognitive prosthesis
  </short-description>
  <medium-description>
    The user awareness component that is responsible for assisting the
    user to  operate on a  reasonable schedule.  It  communicates with
    several other  systems to synthesize highly  logical schedules and
    itineraries.  And most importantly,  it monitors the user's state:
    where  they are,  what they  are  doing, what  their physical  and
    psychological  conditions  are, and  so  forth.   It is  primarily
    responsible  for making  the  user aware  of their  environmental,
    needs and responsibilities.
  </medium-description>
  <long-description>
    <p>
      Manager  has evolved  to be  a central  component in  the FRDCSA
      design, although it isn't yet operational.
    </p>
    <p>
      Communication with  other systems involves:  carrying on dialogs
      with  the user (Audience)  to accomplish  tasks (PSE)  via plans
      (Verber) and  other planning modules (BusRoute  / Event-System /
      Meeting / etc).  However, it  must know certain things about the
      user's habits (RSR),  preferences (CRITIC), background knowledge
      (CLEAR),  and environment  (PhysicalSecurity /  Machiavelli), in
      order to synthesize coherent schedules.
    </p>
    <p>
      Here is a sample of the presence detection system in action:
      <pre>
	Broadcast, person has arrived at 20050109211125
	Broadcast, person has departed at 20050109211131
	Broadcast, person has arrived at 20050109211141
	Broadcast, person has departed at 20050109211206
	Broadcast, person has arrived at 20050109211208
	Broadcast, person has departed at 20050109211351
	Broadcast, person has arrived at 20050109211404
      </pre>
    </p>
    <p>
      It  will  therefore autonomously  execute  certain actions:  for
      instance,  briefing the  user on  destination and  safety before
      driving,  tasks  upon  waking  up,  initiating  sleep  learning,
      reminding  the user  to perform  basic chores  when appropriate,
      frequent  hand  exercise,  bathroom  and sleep  breaks,  keep  a
      polyphasic sleep schedule,
    </p>
    <p>
      It derives much, conceptually, from the Friday and Electric
      Elves system from ISI, as well as many other awareness systems.
      Currently, it interacts heavily with MKAS, and in the future
      will provide capabilities to SVRE.
    </p>
    <p>
      To quote a rather illicit source as read to me by CLEAR:

      <em>
	The Magician must therefore take the utmost care in the matter
	of purification, "firstly", of himself, "secondly", of his
	instruments, "thirdly", of the place of working.  Ancient
	Magicians recommended a preliminary purification of from three
	days to many months.  During this period of training they took
	the utmost pains with diet.  They avoided animal food, lest
	the elemental spirit of the animal should get into their
	atmosphere.  They practised sexual abstinence, lest they
	should be influenced in any way by the spirit of the wife.
	Even in regard to the excrements of the body they were equally
	careful; in trimming the hair and nails, they ceremonially
	destroyed the severed portion.  They fasted, so that the body
	itself might destroy anything extraneous to the bare necessity
	of its existence.  They purified the mind by special prayers
	and conservations.  They avoided the contamination of social
	intercourse, especially the conjugal kind; and their servitors
	were disciples specially chosen and consecrated for the work.
      </em>
    </p>
  </long-description>
  <links>
    <link>
      http://www.w3.org/TR/2000/NOTE-voicexml-20000505/
    </link>
  </links>
</system>
